Let's continue with our next programming assignment where you'll actually
我们继续接下来的编程任务 你需要
build a Kalman filter that can take in lidar measurements and
实现一个卡尔曼滤波器 该滤波器可以代入
track a pedestrian in 2D.
激光雷达测量值并在二维平面上追踪行人
That's pretty cool.
这非常酷
The State Vector of a pedestrian is described by px py position
行人的状态向量使用位置 px、py
vx vy velocity.
和速度 vx、vy 表示
I will give you some starter code, but
我会给你一些开始代码
I want you to set out the rest of the Kalman filter variables.
我希望你能设置其余的卡尔曼滤波器变量
This time, the code is structured into three main parts, a KalmanFilter class,
这次 代码分为三个主要部分：一个KalmanFilter 类
a Tracking class, and a MeasurementPackage class.
一个 tracking 类 以及一个 MeasurementPackage 类
Here I have the KalmanFilter class, the cpp file and
这里是 KalmanFilter 类、cpp 文件和
the corresponding header file.
对应的头文件
This is what you've already coded but the whole KalmanFilter code including
这是你已经编写的代码 但整个 KalmanFilter 代码
its predict and update functions is now decoupled from the tracking logic.
包括预测和更新函数 现在已经从追踪逻辑中分离了
We also have a Tracking class where we actually create and
我们还有一个追踪类 可以创建并使用
use a KalmanFilter object.
一个 KalmanFilter 对象
For this quiz, you're going to modify F and Q matrices
在这个小练习里 你需要根据当前和之前测量值之前的时间差
according to the elapsed time between the current and previous measurement.
修改 F 和 Q 矩阵
You can do so inside the process measurement function.
你可以在过程测量函数内部操作
Afterwards, your code should call the KalmanFilter predict and
然后 你的代码就可以调用 KalmanFilter 预测和
update functions.
更新函数了
Just keep in mind that all the KalmanFilter matrices,
记住 所有卡尔曼滤波器矩阵
as well as the predict update functions are members of the kf_ object.
以及预测更新函数 都是kf 对象的成员
There is a big difference between this and previous programming assignment.
这次编程作业和之前有很大差异
Here, we don't process the entire list of measurements, but
这里 我们没有处理整个测量值列表
rather the most recent measurement.
而是最近的测量值
We are simulating a more realistic scenario where the process measurement
我们在模拟一个更真实的场景
function is called every time we receive new data from a given sensor which,
在每次收到给定传感器的数据时 都会调用过程测量函数
in this case, is only from a laser scanner.
在本例中 传感器是激光扫描仪
Also, the sensor data is organized in package objects now.
此传感器数据以包对象的形式体现
These measurement packages are passed as an argument to the process measurement
这些测量包作为参数传递到过程测量
function.
函数
As you see here,
你可以看到
the package properties are grouped into MeasurementPackage class.
包属性分成不同的测量包类分组
So this class is composed of a timestamp_ variable,
因此 这个类包括一个时间戳变量
which is a point in time where the measurement was created by a sensor and
时间戳是一个时间点 说明了传感器产生测量值的时间
an enum variable called SensorType with two options, LASER and RADAR.
还包括一个非变量 SensorType 它有两个选项：激光和雷达
This is not important right now, as you will only see laser measurement.
现在这不重要 因为你只能看到激光测量
And there is also vector variable with most recent raw measurements.
此还有包括了最新原始测量值的向量变量
Specifically, if MeasurementPackage comes from a laser sensor,
需要特别说明的是 如果测量包来自激光传感器
then the raw_measurements_ vector will contain just observed x and y position.
那么原始测量向量就只包括观察到的 x 和 y 位置
And here is an example of retrieving my data from MeasurementPackage.
这是一个从测量包获取数据的例子
You'll see the x measurement, the y measurement and the timestamp.
你能看到 x、y 测量值和时间戳
And if we print out these values, the result would be something like this.
如果我们打印出这些值 结果就是这样
The x position, the y position and the timestamp.
x、y 测量值和时间戳
The big number assigned to the timestamp variable,
分配给时间戳变量的这个大数字
is the number of microseconds that have elapsed since Thursday, January 1,
单位是微秒 计时开始时间是1970年 1 月 1 日 星期四
1970 which obviously always increases.
很显然 这个变量会始终增加
I would like to point out that in this programing assignment the tracking code
需要指出的是 在这个编程任务中 追踪代码
will first call the predict function and then measurement update function.
会首先调用预测函数 然后才是测量更新函数
And that is because our prediction depends on the elapsed time between
这是因为 我们的预测取决于两次测量之间的
two measurements, and the time is not fixed anymore.
时间差 而且时间不再固定
So we can predict our state only after next observation timestamp is available.
因此 我们只有获得下次的观察时间戳之后 才能预测状态
Basically we have to wait for the next process measurement call, and
也就是说 我们必须等待下次过程测量调用
then to apply the prediction, right before the next measurement update.
然后在下次测量更新之前应用预测
The first process measurement call will just initialize the state position with
第一次过程测量调用在更新状态位置时
the first x and y measurement and the state velocity vx,
只会使用第一次的 x、y 测量值 并且状态速度 vx
vy with 0, assuming we don't know the initial velocity and that's it.
vy 为零 因为我们假定不知道初始速度
Remember if you're having trouble,
记住 如果碰到问题
the steps you need to take are written as a comment in the code.
可以在代码注释中找到所需步骤
Good luck.
祝你好运